MICHAEL CAVALLARO

Portland, OR 97206 · 512-550-8481

mdcavallaro@gmail.com · https://www.linkedin.com/in/michael-cavallaro-5a3940130/ · https://mdcavallaro.github.io/

I am a detail oriented, hardworking, organized, go-getter that puts 100% into any task that is put in front of me. I have experience working in a fast-paced tech start-up with ever changing expectations and deadlines. This along with other experiences has made me an adaptable and agile asset for any team I am a part of.

SKILLS

- Programming Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL and Databases, and Python.
- GitBash
- IDE: Visual Studio Code, Visual Studio Community, Notepad++.
- QA Assurance: UI/UX Testing on Android, iOS and Windows machines, asset management, writing up bug reports, problem solving, critical thinking and analysis.
- Adobe Creative Suite: Illustrator, InDesign, Photoshop.
- Microsoft Office Suite
- Procreate
- JIRA Atlassian Cloud (Task Manager)
- Customer Service and Shipping Programs: Zendesk, Pirate Ship, Chargify, MailChimp, WordPress.

EXPERIENCE

OCTOBER 2019 – NOVEMBER 2019

KEY TECHNOLOGIES USED: HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT, SQL & DATABASES, PYTHON, DJANGO TEMPLATE LANGUAGE, VISUAL STUDIO CODE, GITBASH.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER INTERN, PROSPER IT CONSULTING

This two-week internship focused on using Python and the Django Template Language to solve problems and complete tasks. During this time I participated in morning stand-ups where I briefed the project manager and other team members about the work I completed the previous day, what tasks I was going to be working on that day, and any roadblocks that I was facing. This experience was extremely valuable in providing insight into the daily life of a software developer.

SEPTEMBER 2018 – FEBRUARY 2019

KEY TECHNOLOGIES USED: ZENDESK, CHARGIFY, MAILCHIMP, WORDPRESS, MICROSOFT OFFICE SUITE.

CUSTOMER SUPPORT, SUBSCRIPTION CATALYST LLC

I worked with customers to resolve problems they encountered within the subscription sphere. I also took on the task of processing the End of Day reports and scheduling email campaigns through MailChimp. In taking on this task, I created detailed documents going through the step by step process of completing these tasks and trained the other Customer Support team members on this process as well.

JULY 2015 – AUGUST 2018

KEY TECHNOLOGIES USED: JIRA - ATLASSIAN CLOUD, CREATING AUTOMATED TEST PLANS, ADOBE ILLUSTRATOR, ADOBE PHOTOSHOP, TESTING ON IOS ANDROID AND WINDOWS MACHINES.

LEAD QA ANALYST, BLUE GOJI

As a Lead QA Analyst, I tested application functionality across multiple platforms in order to determine their efficacy and quality. I diagnosed bugs and wrote up detailed reports on any new or recurring issues. I filed these reports into the bug tracking and project management software JIRA. These reports would include all the specifics relating to the issue as well as reproduction steps for developers to be able to resolve these issues. I also coordinated with project managers to create and assign any new tasks necessary for any new features or updates and assigned these tasks to the appropriate team or specific developer. I also worked closely with project managers on the development of user experience and gameplay. During my time at Blue Goji, I also worked several conferences where we would demo our software and hardware to the public and educate them about the company and its goals.

JULY 2015 – AUGUST 2015

KEY TECHNOLOGIES USED: ADOBE ILLUSTRATOR

INTERNSHIP, MAKEATX

At this internship at makeATX, a laser engraving studio in Austin, Tx, I worked on product and packaging development and design using laser engravers and other new techniques. I designed a hangtag for one of their tote bags and learned how to use the laser engravers to produce more inventory in their product line.

NOVEMBER 2012 – FEBRUARY 2014

MOBILE SALES ASSOCIATE, BEST BUY

Assisted customers with trouble shooting mobile hardware, software and sales issues. I eventually grew into a leadership role where I trained new mobile department sales employees. I continually hit or exceeded my monthly and quarterly sales goals, and had customers that would come into the store requesting specifically to work with me.

EDUCATION

NOVEMBER 2019

PYTHON DEVELOPER BOOTCAMP, THE TECH ACADEMY

This Python Developer course introduced me to the following programming languages; HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL, and Python. This course also included sections covering Version Control, Project Management, as well as a two-week live project where I worked with a team to resolve problems and provided daily reports to a project manager. During this live project, I also learned more about the Django Template Language in order to navigate the Python project and utilized GitBash to check out projects and navigate files and folders.

MAY 2017

B.A. IN GRAPHIC DESIGN, ST. EDWARDS UNIVERSITY

I majored in Graphic Design with a focus on Communications at St. Edwards University. At my time at St. Edwards in the design program, I learned about the principles of design and how to use the Adobe CC suite. I completed a variety of different projects for both print and web design.